# JASON R. DOMINIC

Technical Sr. Project Manager/VoIP Architect/Cloud Architect 1116 W Peninsular St, Tampa, FL, 33603 · 813-508-7813 Currently based in Poznan Poland

jadomini@gmail.com

omprojekts.us

Professional Project/Program Manager with experience working with teams to accomplish short and long-term project goals, manage budgets, and monitor project costs. A team leader experienced in directing activities of workgroups, develop strategies, provide training, set goals, and obtain team feedback. Excellent interpersonal and communication skills. Big picture focus with excellence in communicating goals and vision to succeed. Problem solver, networker, and consensus builder.

## **EDUCATION**

08/2022 - CURRENT

MASTER OF SCIENCE: CLOUD COMPUTING, UNIVERSITY OF MARYLAND GLOBAL CAMPUS

01/1993 - 06/1996

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE: EDUCATION, UNIVERSITY OF SOUTH FLORIDA

## CERTIFICATIONS

- PMP Project Management Professional (Cert # 2039358)
- Scrum Master (Cert # 83740819221362)
- Six Sigma Lean Black Belt Professional (Cert # 8970796)
- ITILv3 Foundations (Cert # 03512008-01-GNQG)
- Security+ (Cert # COMP001020758748)
- SCP Solar Winds Certified Professional
- MCSE 2000 (Cert # B318-1015)
- Microsoft Certified Azure Fundamentals (Cert# H175-8318)
- KANBAN Certified Project Manager (Cert # 94155918676406)

- PCEP Certified Entry Level Python Programmer
- CASP+ (Cert# COMP001020762402)
- AWS Cloud Practitioner (Cert# MQVKYKV2C1VQ1XGE)
- Google Certified IT Support Professional
- Google IT Automation with Python Professional
- Microsoft Certified Professional (Cert # B318-1013)
- Microsoft MTA: Cloud Fundamentals (Cert # G737-5437)
- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate (Cert# HXWH8PBCKB141G5V) – Expired 12/20
- SCRUM Developer Accredited Certification (Cert # 51222065825946)

## **SKILLS**

- Cloud Services
- Network Infrastructure
- Switching and Routing
- SolarWinds Support
- Process Improvement
- Project Management
- Cloud Architect
- Data Center
   Management
- VoIP & PBX Design
- Python
- Automation
- Unified Communication
- Voicemail
- ICDS installation
- Agile Project Management
- Lean Manufacturing & Design
- Disaster Recovery & Coop
- SCRUM

## SECURITY CLEARANCE

Active TS/SSBI SCI Eligible – Adjudicated 11/2020

## **KEY EXPERIENCE**

- Supervision of cross platform teams ranging from 5 members to 80+
- Large scale project management
- 16 years experience in management of cross culture teams ranging in Size from 5 FTEs to 70 FTEs
- 17 years experience Program/Project Management
- 16 years experience in Windows based server administration
- 15 years experience in management and implementation of a switched Ethernet infrastructure
- 15 years experience with design and installation of interior and campus wide cable infrastructure
- 13 years experience with Cisco CallManager design, installation, and maintenance
- 13 years experience with Cisco Unity Unified Messaging design, installation, and maintenance
- Project Architect for 10 green field Nortel PBX implementations, including but not limited to design, bid process, vendor selection, and installation
- Project Architect on 10 green field installations, 6 SRST installations, and 8 major release upgrades of Cisco CallManager.
- Project Architect on installation and rollout of 5000+ node Cisco Unity.
- Project Architect on design and implementation of 5000+ node migration from Nortel Option 81+ to
   Cisco UCM 8.6 including Unity, UCCX, E911, and Unified Presence with LYNC and Jabber integration.
- Project Lead of complete Data Center migration.

## WORK HISTORY

08/2021 - CURRENT

## SITE LEAD & SR. PROJECT/TASK MANAGER

GDIT, POZNAN POLAND

- Responsible for developing and managing complex projects to include developing and managing customer expectations, deliverables, schedules, time, and scope.
- Managed and was responsible for successful completion of all tasks in assigned project.
- Maintained staff by recruiting, selecting, orienting, and training new team members; maintaining safe and secure work environment; developing personal growth opportunities.
- Contributed to team effort by assisting team members with accomplishing milestone deliverables.
- Scheduled and facilitated meetings between project stakeholders to discuss deliverables, schedules, and conflicts.
- Maintained open communication by presenting regular updates on project status to customers.
- Tracked project and team member performance closely to quickly intervene in mistakes or delays.
- Built successful project plans covering objectives, resources and staffing to meet schedules.

- Maintained energy and enthusiasm in fast-paced environment.
- Prepared variety of different written communications, reports and documents to ensure smooth operations.
- Offered friendly and efficient service to customers, handled challenging situations with ease.
- Completed projects by coordinating resources and timetables with internal teams and external
  organizations.
- Created plans and communicated deadlines to ensure projects were completed on time.

## 08/2019 - 08/2021

## SR. VOICE ARCHITECT – LEAD ASSOCIATE

BOOZ ALLEN HAMILTON, DISA SE53 EVOIP/ECVOIP, FORT MEADE, MD

- Designed and engineered Voice and Periphery Systems within Global Defense Information Systems Agency (DISA).
- Mentored and guided 10 employees to foster proper completion of assigned duties.
- Lead Architect/Engineer on Voice Cloud Access Point initiative.
- Participated in continuous improvement by generating suggestions, engaging in problem-solving activities to support teamwork.
- Prepared variety of different written communications, reports, and documents to ensure smooth operations.
- Created plans and communicated deadlines to ensure projects were completed on time.
- Used critical thinking to break down problems, evaluate solutions and make decisions.

#### 11/2018 - 08/2019

## PROGRAM MANAGER / TECHNICAL OPERATIONS MANAGER

DIRECTVIZ SOLUTIONS LLC, DISA ID6 TS&M, FORT MEADE, MD

- Management responsibility for successful completion of all tasks in assigned program area including technical work, financial and business development activities.
- Management and career development for 45 fulltime and Sub-contracted employees on multiple cross culture teams.
- Security.
- Networks.
- Systems.
- Sustainment.
- Service Desk.
- Responsible for profitability and revenue growth of assigned program.
- Performed program financial management services, including financial analysis, budget and cost quote preparation, cost management, reconciliation, and profit enhancement.

05/2018 - 11/2018

TRANSITIONAL PROGRAM MANAGER / STRATEGIC PLANNER

## DIRECTVIZ SOLUTIONS LLC, DISA PEST, FORT MEADE, MD

- Management responsibility for successful completion of all tasks in assigned program during transition of newly awarded contract including staffing, technical work, financial and business development activities.
- Interviewed and staffed team with 40 architects, engineers, cybersecurity, physical security, and administrative.
- Management and career development for 45 fulltime and Sub-contracted employees on multiple cross culture teams.
- Security.
- Networks.
- Systems.

#### 02/2017 - 04/2018

# SITE MANAGER / PROGRAM MANAGER

## GDIT, UNITED STATES FORCES KOREA - USACISA-P, SEOUL, KOREA

- Management responsibility for successful completion of all tasks in assigned program area including technical work, financial and business development activities.
- Management and career development for 50 fulltime employees and 25 Sub-contracted employees consisting of US and Korean National staff.
- Security.
- Networks.
- Systems.
- Web Development.
- Service Desk.
- Training.
- Procurement.
- Administrative.
- Managed staff in 5 Permanent sites and 7 Remote sites.
- Responsible for profitability and revenue growth of assigned program.
- Performed program financial management services, including financial analysis, budget and cost quote preparation, cost management, reconciliation, and profit enhancement.
- Supervised contractor work processes and adherence to project schedules.

## 04/2014 - 02/2017

## PRINCIPAL NETWORK ENGINEER & TEAM LEAD

## GDIT, NATO SPECIAL OPERATION HEAD QUARTERS, MONS, BELGIUM

- Supervised a team of 7 highly skilled Network Engineers responsible for Design, Installation, and O&M
  of 3 separate networks including all deployable operations.
- COMSEC Management.
- Lead design and implementation of all Voice Systems.

- Supported and maintained Cisco UCM 8.6 cluster consisting of 3 virtual servers and 350 endpoints including Jabber.
- Designed and implemented Cisco UCM 10.0 cluster for Test Environment.
- Designed and implemented Cisco UCM 10.5 cluster including Unity, UCCX, IMP with Jabber.
- Designed wireless infrastructure for onsite classroom facilities.
- Lead design, operations, and maintenance for daily support of NUN and BICES data networks.

#### 08/2006 - 04/2014

## SR. TECHNOLOGY ARCHITECT

MOFFITT CANCER CENTER, TAMPA, FL

- Guided and influenced existing partners on recommended upgrades and enhancements to integrated solutions.
- Worked with customers or prospective customers to develop integrated solutions and lead detailed architectural dialogues to facilitate delivery of comprehensive solution.
- Lead design and implementation of all Voice Systems within multi campus environment.
- Support and maintenance of Cisco Call Manager 4.0 cluster consisting of 6 Windows NT servers and 1500 endpoints.
- Design, implementation, and support of 5 server Contact Center.
- Microsoft OCS integration using SIP trunks to Nortel CSE1000 and Cisco Call Manager Cluster and support for 2000+ user base.
- Design and Installation of new voice system for 400 user complex built in 2009.
- Installation and support of hospital wide Vocera Communications system consisting of 2 Windows 2008 servers and SIP integration with Nortel CSE 1000.
- Installed and administered 2 Windows 2008 servers running Emergin 10.
- Designed and installed 500 user Spectralink wireless system including both 900Mhz and WAP endpoints.
- Designed and Installed new voice system for 500 user complex built in 2011.
- Design, installation and support of Cisco Call Manger 8.6 cluster on UCS environment integrated with Nortel CSE 1000 using both SIP trunks and PRI trunks.
- Design, installation, and support of business wide RFID staff, patient, and equipment real time tracking system.
- Researched and developed all future voice directions for research center.

## 10/1997 - 08/2006

## **GLOBAL VOICE EGINEER**

CARGILL INC AND THE MOSAIC COMPANY, RIVERVIEW, FL

- Lead design and implementation of all Voice Systems.
- Assisted in design and implementation of all Data Systems.
- Researched and developed cellular solution for global environment.
- Manage and sustain all LAN line voice communications and voice cabling infrastructure.

- Managed cellular communications.
- Maintained key telecom vendor relationships.
- Project management for all telecom related issues.
- Managed and maintained \$1.4 million budget.
- Supervision of all contracted labor for telecoms and infrastructure related issues.